Italian Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- C (Box 35)
  - Individual Artists C., 2031 (Box 36)
    - Ciardi, Guglielmo, 1843-1917., 3 (Box 53)
    - Cigoli, Ludovico Cardi, 1559-1613., 10 (Box 53)
    - Cima da Conigliano, 1459-1517., 74 (Box 53)
      - Locations not noted., 7 (Box 53)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 37 (Box 53)
      - Milan., 9 (Box 53)
      - Venice., 21 (Box 54)
    - Cimabue, Giovanni, 1240-1302., 61 (Box 54)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 10 (Box 54)
      - Assisi., 29 (Box 54)
      - Florence., 16 (Box 54)
      - Turin., 6 (Box 54)
    - Conca, Sebastiano, 1679-1764., 6 (Box 54)
    - Conti, Bernardino de', 1450-1525., 10 (Box 54)
    - Coppo di Marcovaldo, active 1260-1274., 14 (Box 54)
    - Correggio, Antonio Allegri, 1494-1534., 175 (Box 54)
      - Drawings., 21 (Box 55)
      - Paintings., 154 (Box 55)
        - Private collections or location not noted., 8 (Box 55)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 34 (Box 55)
        - Dresden., 9 (Box 55)
        - Florence., 6 (Box 55)
        - London., 12 (Box 55)
        - Naples., 6 (Box 55)
        - Paris., 8 (Box 56)
        - Parma., 55 (Box 56)
        - Rome., 10 (Box 56)
        - Washington, D.C., 6 (Box 57)
    - Cortona, Pietro da, 1596-1669., 35 (Box 57)
      - Drawings., 13 (Box 57)
      - Paintings., 22 (Box 57)
    - Cossa, Francesco, 1435-1478., 56 (Box 57)
      - Drawings., 2 (Box 57)
      - Paintings., 54 (Box 57)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 15 (Box 57)
        - Ferrarra., 31 (Box 58)
        - Washington, D.C., 8 (Box 58)
    - Costa, Lorenzo, 1460-1535., 40 (Box 58)
    - Cozza, Francesco, 1605-1682., 5 (Box 58)
    - Cozzarelli, Guidoccio, 1450-1516., 13 (Box 59)
    - Credi, Lorenzo di, 1456-1537., 79 (Box 59)
      - Drawings., 14 (Box 59)
      - Paintings., 65 (Box 59)
        - Locations not noted., 13 (Box 59)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 28 (Box 59)
        - Florence., 24 (Box 60)
    - Crespi, Daniele, c.1600-1630., 3 (Box 60)
    - Crespi, Giovanni Batista, 1576-1632., 5 (Box 60)
    - Crespi, Giuseppe Maria, 1665-1747., 22 (Box 60)
    - Cristiani, Giovanni di Bartolomeo, active 1360-1398., 12 (Box 60)
    - Crivelli, Carlo, 1430-1495., 87 (Box 60)
      - Locations not noted., 4 (Box 60)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 32 (Box 61)
      - London., 19 (Box 61)
      - Milan., 13 (Box 61)
      - New York., 6 (Box 61)
      - Rome., 7 (Box 61)
      - Washington, D.C., 6 (Box 61)
    - Crivelli, Vittore, active 1465-1501., 4 (Box 62)
- D (Box 62)
  - Miscellaneous Artists D., 40 (Box 62)
    - Daddi, Cosimo, -1630., 1 (Box 62)
    - Dalbino, Edoardo, XIX C., 1 (Box 62)
    - Dalmasio, c.1325-1375., 1 (Box 62)
    - Damini, Vincenzo, active 1720-1730., 1 (Box 62)
    - D'Ancona, Vito, 1825-1884., 2 (Box 62)
    - Dandini, Cesare, 1595-1658., 5 (Box 62)
    - Daniele da Volterra, 1509-1566., 3 (Box 62)
      Artist also known as Ricciarelli.
    - Decamps, Alexandre-Gabriel, 1803-1860., 1 (Box 62)
    - Delli, Dello, 1404-c.1465., 1 (Box 62)
    - Depero, Fortunato, 1892-1960., 4 (Box 62)
    - Diamante, Fra, 1430-c.1498., 1 (Box 62)
    - Diana, Benedetto, active 1460-1525., 2 (Box 62)
    - Diano, Giacinto, 1730-1803., 1 (Box 62)
    - Diziani, Gaspare, 1689-1767., 1 (Box 62)
    - Domenico di Bartolo, 1400-1444/6., 1 (Box 62)
    - Domenico di Melchelino, 1417-1491., 1 (Box 62)
    - Donatello, attributed to., 2 (Box 62)
    - Donato de'Bardi, XV C., 1 (Box 62)
    - Donghi, Antonio, 1897-1963., 1 (Box 62)
    - Dorazio, Piero, 1927-., 3 (Box 62)
    - Dosio, Giovannantonio, 1535-1619., 2 (Box 62)
    - Dossi, Battista di Lutero, 1493-1548., 1 (Box 62)
    - Dottori, Gerardo, 1889-1977., 2 (Box 62)
    - Dudreville, Leonardo, 1885-1975., 1 (Box 62)
  - Individual Artists D., 446 (Box 62)
    - Daddi, Bernardo, active 1328-1350., 75 (Box 62)
      - Locations not noted., 5 (Box 62)
      - Private collections., 4 (Box 62)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 27 (Box 62)
      - Florence., 13 (Box 62)
      - London., 13 (Box 62)
      - New York., 13 (Box 62)
    - Dolce, Carlo, 1616-1686., 31 (Box 63)
    - Domenichino, Zampieri, 1581-1641., 46 (Box 63)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 63)
      - Paintings., 42 (Box 63)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 18 (Box 63)
        - Rome., 24 (Box 63)
    - Domenico di Bartolo, 1400-1449., 31 (Box 63)
      Also known as Ghezzi.
      - Miscellaneous locations., 8 (Box 64)
      - Siena., 23 (Box 64)
    - Domenico, Veneziano, 1390-1461., 52 (Box 64)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 8 (Box 64)
      - Berlin., 11 (Box 64)
      - Florence., 24 (Box 64)
      - Washington, D.C., 9 (Box 65)
    - Dossi, Dosso, 1479-1542., 34 (Box 66)
    - Duccio di Brononsegna, 1255-1339., 169 (Box 66)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 22 (Box 66)
      - Maesta., 73 (Box 66)
        - Front., 21 (Box 66)
        - Rear., 60 (Box 66)
      - Florence., 25 (Box 66)
      - London., 13 (Box 66)
      - New York., 4 (Box 66)
      - Siena., 12 (Box 66)
        Does not include Maesta photographs, which have their own category.
      - School of Duccio., 20 (Box 66)
    - Duranti, Fortunato, 1787-1863., 8 (Box 66)
- E (Box 66)
  - Miscellaneous Artists E., 4 (Box 66)
    - Ercole de Roberti, c.1450-1496., 1 (Box 66)
    - Estense, Baldassare, active 1469-1500., 1 (Box 66)
    - Evola, Giulio, 1898-., 2 (Box 66)
  - Individual Artists E., 12 (Box 66)
    - Erri, Bartolomeo degli, active 1460-1476., 7 (Box 66)
    - Eusebio da San Giorgio, active 1492-1540., 5 (Box 66)
- F (Box 66)
  - Miscellaneous Artists F., 39 (Box 66)
    - Facchetti, Pietro, 1538-1619., 1 (Box 66)
    - Faccini, Pietro, 1562-1602., 1 (Box 66)
    - Falconetto, Giovanni Marie, 1468-1535., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fallani, Mario, XX C., 1 (Box 66)
    - Faruffini, Federico, 1831-1869., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fede, Galizia, 1578-1630., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fei, Alessandro, 1543-1592., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fenzoni, Ferrau, 1562-1648., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fergola, S. XIX C., 1 (Box 66)
    - Ferranese, XV C., 1 (Box 66)
    - Ferrari, Gregorio da, 1644-1726., 2 (Box 66)
    - Ferrazzi, Ferruccio, 1891-1978., 1 (Box 66)
    - Ferre, Natale, 1817-1879., 1 (Box 66)
    - Ficherelli, Felice, 1605-1660., 1 (Box 66)
    - Figino, Girolamo, XVI C., 1 (Box 66)
    - Filarete, Antonio, 1400-1469., 1 (Box 66)
    - Filippo da Verona, active 1509-1515., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fini, Leonor, 1908-., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fiume, Salvatore, 1915-., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fogolino, Marcello, 1470-1550., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fontana, Lavinia (Zappi), 1552-1614., 2 (Box 66)
    - Fontanesi, Antonio, 1818-1882., 1 (Box 66)
    - Fontebasso, Francesco, 1709-1769., 2 (Box 66)
    - Forabosco, Girolamo, 1631-1689., 2 (Box 66)
    - Franceschini, Baldassare, 1611-1689., 3 (Box 66)
      Also known as Il Volterrano.
    - Francesco di Antonio, 1393-1433., 1 (Box 66)
    - Francesco di Vannuccio, c.1361-1388., 2 (Box 66)
    - Francia, Giacomo, 1486-1557., 3 (Box 66)
    - Franco, Battista, 1498-1561., 2 (Box 66)
    - Fumiani, Giovanni Antonio, 1643-1710., 1 (Box 66)
  - Individual Artists F., 530 (Box 66)
    - Falcone, Aniello, 1607-1656., 5 (Box 66)
    - Fattori, Giovanni, 1825-1908., 26 (Box 66)
    - Favretto, Giacomo, 1849-1887., 7 (Box 66)
    - Ferrari, Defendente di, 1481-1546., 6 (Box 66)
    - Ferrari, Gaudenzio, 1470-1549., 23 (Box 66)
    - Fetti, Domenico, 1589-1624., 26 (Box 67)
    - Fiore, Jacopo del, active 1385-1439., 12 (Box 67)
    - Fiorenzo di Lorenzo, 1440-1522., 32 (Box 67)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 8 (Box 67)
      - Perugia., 24 (Box 67)
    - Fontana, Lucio, 1899-1968., 11 (Box 67)
    - Foppa, Vincenzo, c.1425/30-1515/16., 21 (Box 68)
    - Francesco, Piero della, 238 (Box 68)
      - Drawings., 1 (Box 68)
      - Paintings., 236 (Box 68)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 25 (Box 68)
        - Arezzo., 76 (Box 69-, Box 70)
        - Borgo San Sepolcro., 32 (Box 70)
        - Florence., 15 (Box 70)
        - London., 34 (Box 70)
        - Milan., 14 (Box 70)
        - New York., 6 (Box 70)
        - Perugia., 18 (Box 71)
        - Urbino., 16 (Box 71)
      - Suspected forgery., 1 (Box 71)
    - Franceschini, Marc Antonio, 1648-1729., 7 (Box 71)
    - Francesco di Giorgio, 1439-1502., 31 (Box 71)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 9 (Box 71)
      - Siena., 22 (Box 72)
    - Franciabigia, c.1482-1525., 58 (Box 72)
      - Locations not noted., 2 (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 40 (Box 72)
      - Florence., 16 (Box 73)
    - Franco, Giovanni Battista, 1498-1561., 4 (Box 73)
    - Fungai, Bernardino, 1460-1516., 14 (Box 73)
    - Furini, Francesco, 1600-1646., 8 (Box 73)
- G (Box 73)
  - Miscellaneous Artists G., 76 (Box 73)
    - Gabbiani, Anton Domenico, 1652-1726., 1 (Box 73)
    - Galasso di Matteo Piva, XV C., 1 (Box 73)
    - Galgario, Fra, 1655-1743., 1 (Box 73)
    - Galli, Gino, 1893-1945., 2 (Box 73)
    - Galliari, Giovanni, 1680-1720., 2 (Box 73)
    - Gamba, Paolo, 1712-1782., 1 (Box 73)
    - Garbari, Tullio, 1892-1931., 1 (Box 73)
    - Gargulio, Domenico, 1612-1675., 1 (Box 73)
      Also known as Micco Spadaro.
    - Garzi, Luigi, 1638-1721., 1 (Box 73)
    - Garzoni, Giovanna, 1600-1670., 1 (Box 73)
    - Gatti, Annibale, 1828-1909., 1 (Box 73)
    - Gatti, Bernardino, 1475-1576., 2 (Box 73)
    - Gavassetti, Camillo, active 1624., 1 (Box 73)
    - Genga, Girolamo, 1476-1551., 3 (Box 73)
    - Gennari, Benedetto, 1633-1715., 2 (Box 73)
    - Ghedini, Giuseppe, 1707-1791., 1 (Box 73)
    - Gherardi, Fillipo, 1643-1704., 1 (Box 73)
    - Gherardi, Giuseppe, 1788/90-1884., 1 (Box 73)
    - Ghezzi, Pier Leone, 1674-1755., 2 (Box 73)
    - Ghirlandaio, Benedetto, 1458-1497., 2 (Box 74)
      See also Domenico Ghirlandaio, his brother.
    - Giacomo da Milano, active c.1523., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giannicola di Paolo, 1460-1544., 1 (Box 74)
    - Gignous, Eugenio, 1850-1842., 1 (Box 74)
    - Gimignani, Giacinto, 1611-1681., 1 (Box 74)
    - Gimignani, Lucovico, 1643-1697., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giocondo, Gra, c.a433-1515., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giottino, active 1368-1400., 4 (Box 74)
    - Giovanni Battista, active 1495., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giovanni da Modena, XV C., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giovanni da San Giovanni, 1592-1636., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giovanni da Udine, 1487-1564., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giovanni di Bartolommeo Cristiani, active 1366-1398., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giovanni Francesco da Rimini, active c.1441-1470., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giovanni Pietro da Cemmo, 1474-1504., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giovenone, Girolamo, 1486/87-1555., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giulio Romano, 1492-1546., 1 (Box 74)
    - Giunta Pisano, c.1255-1267., 5 (Box 74)
    - Giusto di Jacopo, ?., 1 (Box 74)
      Also known as Grasello.
    - Gordigiani, Michele, 1830-1909., 2 (Box 74)
    - Gramiccia, Lorenzo, 1702-1795., 1 (Box 74)
    - Grammatica, Antiveduto, c.1571-1626., 1 (Box 74)
    - Grandi, Francesco, 1831-1891., 1 (Box 74)
    - Grassi, Nicola, 1682-1750., 1 (Box 74)
    - Gregolini, Antonio, 1675-1736., 1 (Box 74)
    - Gregorio di Cecco di Luca, active 1389-1423., 2 (Box 74)
    - Grigoletti, Michelangelo, 1801-1870., 1 (Box 74)
    - Grisoni, Giuseppe, 1699-1769., 1 (Box 74)
    - Gualdo, Matteo da, active 1468., 1 (Box 74)
    - Guardi, Gian Antonio, c.1699-1760., 1 (Box 74)
    - Guarienti, Carlo, 1923-., 1 (Box 74)
    - Guarino, Francesco, 1611-1654., 3 (Box 74)
    - Guccione, Pietro, 1935-., 1 (Box 74)
    - Guglielmi, Luigi, 1834-1907., 1 (Box 74)
    - Guidi, Virgilio, 1891-1984., 2 (Box 75)
  - Individual Artists G., 1981 (Box 75)
    Giusto di Padua, see Menabudi.
    - Gaddi, Agnolo, 1333-1396., 25 (Box 75)
    - Gaddi, Taddeo, c.1300-1366., 62 (Box 75)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 22 (Box 75)
      - Florence., 40
    - Gandolfi, Gaetano, 1734-1802., 8 (Box 76)
    - Garofolo, Benevenuto Tisi da, 1481-1559., 22 (Box 76)
    - Gaulli, Giovanni Battista, 1639-1709., 20 (Box 76)
    - Gentile da Fabriano, 1370-1427., 82 (Box 76)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 24 (Box 76)
      - Florence., 46 (Box 76)
      - New York., 5 (Box 76)
      - Washington, D.C., 7 (Box 76)
    - Gentileschi, Artemisia, 1597-1651., 19 (Box 76)
    - Gentileschi, Orazio, 1565-1647., 53 (Box 76)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 17 (Box 76)
      - Rome., 19 (Box 76)
        Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings of the Palazzo Rospigliosi-Pallavicini.
      - Washington, D.C., 7 (Box 76)
    - Gerini, Lorenzo di Niccolo, 1368-1440., 16 (Box 77)
    - Gerini, Niccolo di Pietro, active 1368-1415., 7 (Box 77)
    - Ghirlandaio, Domenico, 1449-1494., 309 (Box 77)
      - Drawings., 12 (Box 77)
      - Paintings., 297 (Box 77)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 21 (Box 77)
        - Florence., 233 (Box 77)
          - Miscellaneous locations in Florence., 16 (Box 77)
          - Convent d'Ognisanti., 11 (Box 77)
          - S. Maria Novella., 141 (Box 77)
            - Various subjects., 12 (Box 78)
            - Life of the Virgin., 65 (Box 79)
            - Life of St. John the Baptist., 64 (Box 80-, Box 81)
          - S. Trinita., 59 (Box 81)
            - Various subjects., 16 (Box 81)
            - Life of St. Francis., 43 (Box 82)
          - Uffizi., 6 (Box 82)
        - London., 5 (Box 82)
        - New York., 7 (Box 82)
        - Paris., 4 (Box 82)
        - Rimini., 8 (Box 82)
        - Rome., 12 (Box 82)
        - San Gimignano., 7 (Box 83)
    - Ghirlandaio, Ridolfo, 1483-1561., 17 (Box 83)
    - Ghislandi, Vittore, 1655-1743., 7 (Box 83)
    - Giacometti, Giovanni, 1868-1933., 14 (Box 83)
    - Giani, Felice, 1758-1823., 3 (Box 83)
    - Gianpietrino, active 1500-1525., 9 (Box 83)
      Also known as Giovanni Pietrino Rizzi.
    - Giaquinto, Corrado, 1690-1765., 17 (Box 84)
    - Giordano, Luca, 1632-1705., 61 (Box 84)
      - Locations not noted., 8 (Box 84)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 45 (Box 84)
      - Florence., 8 (Box 85)
    - Giorgone, 1477-1510., 135 (Box 85)
      Also known as Giorgio Barbarelli.
      - Drawings., 6 (Box 85)
      - Paintings., 129 (Box 85)
        - Locations not noted., 3 (Box 85)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 28 (Box 85)
        - Castelfranco., 7 (Box 85)
        - Dresden., 8 (Box 86)
        - Florence., 16 (Box 86)
        - London., 8 (Box 86)
        - Paris., 10 (Box 86)
        - Venice., 15 (Box 86)
        - Vienna., 11 (Box 86)
        - Washington, D.C., 13 (Box 87)
    - Giotto, 1266-1336., 439 (Box 87)
      - Drawings., 2 (Box 87)
      - Paintings., 421 (Box 87)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 13 (Box 87)
        - Assisi., 108 (Box 87)
          - San Francesco, upper church., 65 (Box 87)
            - Miscellaneous scenes., 2 (Box 87)
            - Life of St. Francis., 63 (Box 87)
          - San Francesco, lower church., 43 (Box 87)
            - Miscellaneous scenes., 11 (Box 87)
            - Scenes from the life of Christ., 12 (Box 87)
            - Scenes from the life of St. Francis., 10 (Box 87)
            - Allegories of Virtues., 10 (Box 87)
        - Florence., 72 (Box 87)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 13 (Box 87)
          - S. Croce., 45 (Box 87)
            - Miscellaneous scenes., 3 (Box 87)
            - Bardi Chapel., 31 (Box 87)
            - Peruzzi Chapel., 11 (Box 87)
          - Uffizi., 14 (Box 87)
        - Padua., 211 (Box 87)
          - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 87)
          - Arena Chapel., 210 (Box 87)
            - Miscellaneous scenes and overviews., 15 (Box 87)
            - Allegorical figures., 13 (Box 87)
            - Life of the Virgin., 55 (Box 87)
            - Life of Christ., 127 (Box 87)
        - Rome., 9 (Box 87)
        - Washington, D.C., 8 (Box 87)
      - School of Giotto., 16 (Box 87)
    - Giovanni da Milano, active 1350-1369., 11 (Box 87)
    - Giovanni del Biondo, 1356-1392., 8 (Box 87)
    - Giovanni di Francesco, active 1460., 8 (Box 87)
    - Giovanni di Paolo, 1403-1482., 142 (Box 87)
      - Locations not noted., 7 (Box 87)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 35 (Box 88)
      - Baltimore., 8 (Box 88)
      - Chicago., 18 (Box 88)
      - New York., 32 (Box 89)
      - Siena., 42 (Box 89)
    - Giovannino de Grassi, c.1390-1398., 23 (Box 90)
    - Girolamo di Benvenuto, 1470-1524., 21 (Box 90)
    - Girolamo da Cremona, active 1467-1483., 7 (Box 90)
    - Giulio Romano, 1499-1546., 73 (Box 90)
      - Drawings., 8 (Box 90)
      - Paintings., 65 (Box 90)
        - Miscellaneous locations or not noted., 15 (Box 90)
        - Mantua., 12 (Box 91)
        - New York., 12 (Box 91)
        - Rome., 26 (Box 91)
    - Granacci, Francesco, 1477-1543., 6 (Box 91)
    - Grandi, Ercole di Giulio Cesare, c.1463-1531., 3 (Box 92)
    - Guardi, Francesco, 1712-1793., 161 (Box 92)
      - Drawings., 41 (Box 92)
      - Paintings., 120 (Box 92)
        - Locations not noted., 24 (Box 92)
        - Private collections., 8 (Box 93)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 19 (Box 93)
        - Bergamo., 5 (Box 93)
        - London., 20 (Box 93)
        - Milan., 7 (Box 94)
        - New York., 7 (Box 94)
        - Paris., 8 (Box 94)
        - Venice., 11 (Box 94)
        - Washington, D.C., 11 (Box 94)
    - Guariento Padovano, active 1338-1370., 3 (Box 95)
    - Guercino, 1591-1666., 165 (Box 95)
      - Drawings., 31 (Box 95)
      - Paintings., 134 (Box 95)
        - Private collections and locations not noted., 14 (Box 95)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 86 (Box 96-, Box 97)
        - Rome., 34 (Box 97)
    - Guido da Siena, active 1221-1281., 20 (Box 97)
    - Guttuso, Renato, 1912-., 5 (Box 97)
- H (Box 97)
  - Miscellaneous Artists H., 2 (Box 97)
    - Haimann, Giuseppe, 1828-1883., 2 (Box 97)
  - Individual Artists H., 7 (Box 97)
    - Francesco Hayez, 1791-1882., 7 (Box 97)
- I (Box 97)
  - Miscellaneous Artists I., 7 (Box 97)
    - Ibi, Sinibaldo, 1475-1550., 3 (Box 97)
    - Induno, Domenico, 1815-1878., 2 (Box 97)
    - Ingengo, Andrea di Luigi, active 1484-1516., 1 (Box 97)
    - Innocenzo da Imola, c.1490-1550., 1 (Box 97)
- J (Box 97)
  - Miscellaneous Artists J., 7 (Box 97)
    - Jacobello del Fiore, -1439., 1 (Box 97)
    - Jacobello di Bonomo, XIV C., 1 (Box 97)
    - Jacomo del Pisano, c.1400., 1 (Box 97)
    - Jacovacci, Francesco, 1838-1908., 1 (Box 97)
    - Joli, Antonio, c.1700-1777., 2 (Box 97)
    - Juvarra, Filippo, 1678-1736., 1 (Box 98)
  - Individual Artists J, 6 (Box 98)
    - Jacopo di Cione, active 1368-1394., 6 (Box 98)
- L (Box 98)
  - Individual Artists L., 1595 (Box 98)
    - Landi, Neroccio di, 1447-1500., 39 (Box 98)
    - Landini, Jacopo, 1297-1358., 8 (Box 98)
      Also known as Jacopo del Casentino.
    - Lanfranco, Giovanni, 1582-1647., 21 (Box 99)
    - Lanini, Bernardino, c.1520-c.1578., 5 (Box 99)
    - Laurana, Luciano, 1420/25-1479., 12 (Box 99)
    - Lega, Silvestro, 1826-1895., 20 (Box 99)
    - Leonardo da Vinci, 1452-1519., 468 (Box 99)
      - Portraits of Leonardo., 8 (Box 99)
      - Drawings., 269 (Box 99)
        - General subjects and combined subjects., 20 (Box 99)
        - Allegory., 6 (Box 100)
        - Anatomy., 23 (Box 100)
        - Animals., 35 (Box 100)
        - Figures., 37 (Box 101)
          Includes "Man of Perfect Proportions."
        - Heads and caricatures., 49 (Box 102)
        - Landscapes and plants., 17 (Box 102)
        - Machines., 16 (Box 102)
        - Storms., 7 (Box 102)
        - Studies., 59 (Box 103)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 17 (Box 103)
          - Battle of Anghiari., 12 (Box 103)
          - The Last Supper., 12 (Box 103)
          - Madonna and Child with St. Anne., 18 (Box 103)
      - Paintings., 157 (Box 103)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 12 (Box 103)
        - Florence., 36 (Box 104)
          - The Annunciation., 6 (Box 103)
          - Adoration of the Magi., 30 (Box 103)
        - Leningrad., 3 (Box 103)
        - London., 12 (Box 104)
        - Milan., 42 (Box 104)
          - Miscellaneous works., 8 (Box 104)
          - The Last Supper., 34 (Box 104)
        - Paris., 35 (Box 105)
          - Miscellaneous works., 15 (Box 105)
          - Madonna and Child with St. Anne., 9 (Box 105)
          - Mona Lisa., 11 (Box 105)
        - Rome., 5 (Box 105)
        - Washington, D.C., 12 (Box 105)
      - School of Leonardo., 34 (Box 106)
    - Leoni, Ottavio, 1578-1630., 3 (Box 106)
    - Liberale da Verona, 1451-1536., 5 (Box 106)
    - Libri, Girolamo dai, 1474-1555., 11 (Box 106)
    - Licinio, Bernardino, c.1489-1560., 6 (Box 106)
    - Ligozzi, Jacopo, 1543-1627., 3 (Box 106)
    - Lippi, Filippino, 1457-1504., 176 (Box 106)
      - Drawings., 21 (Box 106)
      - Paintings., 155 (Box 107)
        - Locations not noted., 6 (Box 107)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 35 (Box 107)
        - Florence., 71 (Box 107)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 10 (Box 107)
          - Chiesa di Badia., 11 (Box 107)
          - Chiesa del Carmine., 14 (Box 108)
          - Pitti Palace., 4 (Box 108)
          - Santa Maria Novella., 16 (Box 108)
          - Uffizi., 16 (Box 108)
        - London., 18 (Box 108)
        - Prato., 7 (Box 109)
        - Rome., 14 (Box 109)
        - Toledo., 4 (Box 109)
    - Lippi, Fra Filippo, 1406-1469., 190 (Box 110–112)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 110)
      - Paintings., 185 (Box 110)
      - Suspected forgery., 1 (Box 113)
    - Lippi, Lorenzo, 1606-1665., 3 (Box 113)
    - Locatelli, Andrea, 1695-1741., 4 (Box 113)
    - Longhi, Alessandro, 1753-1813., 4 (Box 113)
    - Longhi, Pietro, 1702-1785., 55 (Box 113)
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 113)
      - Paintings., 50 (Box 113-, Box 114)
    - Lorenzetti, Ambrogio, active1319-1348., 102 (Box 114)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 12 (Box 114)
      - Florence., 18 (Box 114)
      - Siena., 72 (Box 114)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 10 (Box 114)
        - Academy/Accademia/Pinacoteca., 23 (Box 114)
        - Palazzo Comunale/Publico., 39 (Box 114)
          - Allegory of Good Government., 17 (Box 114)
          - Effects of Good Government in the City., 14 (Box 114)
          - Effects of Good Government in the Country., 8 (Box 114)
    - Lorenzetti, Pietro, active1280-1348., 138 (Box 114)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 16 (Box 114)
      - Arezzo., 13 (Box 114)
      - Assisi., 34 (Box 114)
      - Cortona., 5 (Box 114)
      - Florence., 15 (Box 114)
      - Rome., 4 (Box 114)
      - Siena., 29 (Box 114)
      - School of Lorenzetti., 22 (Box 114)
    - Lorenzo D'Alessandro da Sanseverino, active 1468-1503., 5 (Box 114)
    - Lorenzo, Monaco, 1370-1425., 62 (Box 114)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 22 (Box 114)
      - Florence., 33 (Box 114)
      - London., 7 (Box 114)
    - Lorenzo da Viterbo, XV C., 4 (Box 114)
    - Lorenzo Veneziano, active1358-1372., 5 (Box 114)
    - Lotto, Lorenzo, 1480-1556., 94 (Box 114)
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 114)
      - Paintings., 89 (Box 114)
        - Locations not noted., 8 (Box 114)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 47 (Box 114)
        - Bergamo., 11 (Box 114)
        - London., 7 (Box 115)
        - Milan., 6 (Box 115)
        - Washington., 10 (Box 115)
    - Luca di Tomme, 1330-1389., 25 (Box 115)
    - Luini, Bernardino, c.1475-1532., 127 (Box 115)
      - Drawings., 7 (Box 115)
      - Paintings., 120 (Box 115)
        - Locations not noted., 5 (Box 115)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 24 (Box 116)
        - London., 9 (Box 116)
        - Milan., 39 (Box 117)
        - Paris., 6 (Box 117)
        - Saronno., 16 (Box 117)
        - Washington, D.C., 21 (Box 118)
- M (Box 118)
  - Miscellaneous Artists M., 83 (Box 118)
    - Macchietti, Girolamo, 1535-1592., 1 (Box 118)
    - Macrino, D'Alba, c.1470-1528., 3 (Box 118)
    - Maffei, Francesco, c.1620-1660., 4 (Box 118)
    - Magiotto, XVIII C., 1 (Box 118)
    - Magnelli, Alberto, 1888-1971., 1 (Box 118)
    - Maineri, Gian Francesco, -c.1504., 1 (Box 118)
    - Mancini, Antonio, 1852-1930., 4 (Box 118)
    - Mancini, Francesco, 1694-1758., 2 (Box 118)
    - Manzoni, Piero, 1933-1963., 2 (Box 118)
    - Manzu, Giacomo, 1908-., 2 (Box 118)